<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Tesla-Coil on Skylake&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://skylakc.github.io/tags/tesla-coil/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Tesla-Coil on Skylake&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skylakc.github.io/tags/tesla-coil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>My tesla coils</title>
        <link>https://skylakc.github.io/p/my-tesla-coils/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://skylakc.github.io/p/my-tesla-coils/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://skylakc.github.io/p/my-tesla-coils/coil.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My tesla coils" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me and lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The duration of this project spanned my middle school and undergraduate years, and with each new location I always wanted to improve the design and implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beginning&#34;&gt;Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I just wanna make a switching power supply. When I was came across to the NE555 chip, I found the mystery of AC world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a CD4046 based PLL Driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=4013.jpg width=60% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I changed my target and make a inverter. At the same time, I searched a interesting device which could released over 1,000,000 voltages. It was invented by Nicola Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the load of my inverter is Tesla Coil. To verified the functions of the coil, my first target is make a SGTC (Spark Gap Tesla Coil).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=sgtc.jpg width=60% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a HV generator and a inverter. At that time, I was a junior high school student. So my solution is Classical ZVS inverter + CRT Line output transformer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=zvs1.jpg width=60% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the arc of the output, 15kV DC Apporx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=arc.png width=60% /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gen-1&#34;&gt;Gen 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To replace the spark gap, we need to artificially control the coil with chips and transistors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All circuit cited from Steve UD1.3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based 74HC74/74HC08/74HC04&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The isolator is HFBT1414/HFBT2412 ST Optical Fiber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interrupt signal transmitted through Fiber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=driver1.jpg width=60% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inverter, I chose full bridge topology. The IGBT driver used magnetical isolatator (GDT, Gate Driver Transformer, made of Ethernet Wire)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=inverter.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To control the working duration, I designed a interrupt signal generator. It based on NE555 and LM393.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=interrupter.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the testing site. The MCU responsible for generating a fake primary working excitation to trig the D trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=testing.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the oscilloscope result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=testing2.jpg width=50% /&gt;
&lt;img src=testing6.jpg width=50% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the current sensor and feedback sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=sensor.jpg width=50% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I mounted the relevant equipment to the coil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=primarycoil.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;img src=interrupter.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I got the whole device and I decided to test in my home. I have made a total of two coils based on different calculation parameters. My mom and dad helped me with the winding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=test.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;img src=coil0.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;img src=coil1.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, the result is not good. I have to change my solution and debug the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gen-2&#34;&gt;Gen 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the prompt, I reached out to the CPLD. Here are the next gen. driver.
The solution based on CPLD Altera MAX II, which integrated whole door circuit into one chip.
The new GDT driver used P-N MOSFET FDD8424H to instead of IRFP540/9540 totem pole MOS amplifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=driver2.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, I recalculated the resonance parameters, taking into account the conclusions of enthusiasts in other parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=testing3.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time the result is very significant, at this point the resonant current has reached 100Amps according to the calculation, the IGBT is rated at 50Amps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to be able to use the previous secondary coil and get better results, I set out to improve a new generation of inverters, this time with 5 IGBTs per arm in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=inverter2.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tested the coil at my home and my high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=testing4.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;img src=testing5.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;twisting&#34;&gt;Twisting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time went by I came to the university, because of some trivial things, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t concentrate on doing higher power testing. So I switched to doing some optimization design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the new gen. driver based on CPLD Xilinx CoolRunner II.
In this board, I tried to design some protect circuit and faster PWM Signal in CPLD.
Such as a Phase shift circuit to protect the IGBT.
Also, I add a isolated IGBT driver though Fiber to instead of Gate Driver Transformer(GDT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=driver3.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new platform in my lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=coil4.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this time, I tried to use the IGBT modules to build the full bridge inverter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=inverter3.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But It didn&amp;rsquo;t last long, as the program was quickly suspended by the school and terminated after I lobbied ineffectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rebirth&#34;&gt;Rebirth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart, new life&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember when I was in my third year of junior high school, my dad gave me 3,000 RMB to realize my dream, and in that year, I built an oversized IGBT inverter. But the lack of theoretical knowledge made me never successfully and safely drive up this big guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=inverter5.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the resonant capacitors prepared at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=cap1.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is the secondary coil that was prepared at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=coil.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I did my graduation defense, I was reminded again of my childhood aspirations, so I redesigned the new driver circuit.   The new driver based on Infineon Cypress PSoc, which integrated in FPGA, PGA and ARM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I developed a GUI base on Node.js. It is a digital operate pannel with various sensor data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=teslanode.jpg width=80% /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that someday I can actually finish and close this 10-year project!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
